这是在圣所的录音
This is the recording from Sanctuary.
－这是什么    －一段祷文
- What is it? - A prayer.
站住   钴队到底在哪里
- Stand down! - Where is COBALT Team?
我给予你们祝福 致远星的人们
"I bring you blessings, people of Reach."
约翰 117已被解除外勤资格
John-117 is relieved from active duty,
在他通过精神评估之前
and will be confined to barracks till such time
不得离开军营
as he clears a psychiatric evaluation.
他们给改了
They changed it!
要知道我来时无有慈悲
"Know that I have come without mercy."
你担心约翰的精神健康状况吗
Do you have concerns about John's mental state?
不管采取什么行动 我所有的模拟
All of my simulations return the same result,
都反馈回了相同的结果
regardless of any action taken.
所以没什么能做的
So there's nothing to be done.
无有怜悯
"Without pity."
星盟有人几天前袭击了钻队
The Covenant element hit COBALT Team days ago.
我们可以假设星盟舰队就在不远处
We can assume the Covenant Fleet isn't far behind.
－我们现在不能和他们交于－我们只能反击
- We're not gonna fight. - We're going to fight.
只是我们赢不了
We're just not going to win.
就在我们说话这会儿
Essential assets are being
重要资产正被运出这颗星球
transported off the planet as we speak.
我能指望你吗
Can I count on you?
要知道我是灭亡你们的工具
"Know that I am the instrument of your extinction."
我要找佩雷斯下士
I need to speak with Corporal Perez.
我将此星球
"I bring this planet forth
献为燔祭
as a burnt offering.
于这祭坛上
Upon this altar,
我放上恶魔的头颅
I place the head of the Demon."
你说过还有别的生活方式
You said there were other ways to live.
没错
That's right.
比如什么
Like what?
祝圣我的人民伟大的旅程
"And consecrate the Great Journey of my people.
要知道我是瓦尔加塔奈
Know that I am Var 'Gatanai.
要知道我是 死神
Know that I am Death."
他们已经来了
They're already here.
对不对
Aren't they?
来点夜宵
Got a little late-night supper here.
你好 本尼  詹妮
Hello, Benny. Uh, Jenny.
你好 莱尼
Hello, Lenny.
基斯
Keith.
冷静点 你们有什么毛病吗
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Settle down. What's up with you guys?
够你们所有鸟吃的
There's enough for everyone.
进去 快进去
Go inside! Go inside!
－这边走     －我要回家
- This way. - I need to get home!
佩雷斯
Perez!
我得去看看我的家人
I need to see my family.
不行 快来
No, come on.
－我得去找我的家人    －嘿
- I need to get to my family! - Hey!
下士 他们走了
Corporal! They're gone.
放开我 我得去找我的家人
Let me go! I need to see my family!
快点 快点 这边 快点
Come on! Come on! This way! Come on!
别跟我说你刚刚没感觉到
Don't try to tell me you didn't feel that one.
外面出事了
Something's going on out there.
你知道我们在打仗吧
You're aware there's a war?
那也是遥远的殖民地在打
In the outer colonies.
这就是战争
Well, that's the thing about war.
它永远不会停留在战争开始的地方
It never stays where you put it.
很高兴见到你 索伦
It is good to see you, Soren.
也很高兴知道你还活着
To know you're still alive.
－我不知道该说什么！－这倒是新鲜
- I don't know what to say. - Well, that's unlike you.
你很了解我吗
How would you know?
我在脑了里想了上干遍了
I've played this over in my head a thousand times.
该说些什么
What to say.
怎么说
How to say it.
如果我能再和你共外一室我会怎么做
What I would do if I were ever in the same room with you again.
然后呢
And?
你的个头比我记忆中的要小
You're smaller than I remember.
看来还是有好处的
There's your upside.
场区外围可能还带电
The field perimeter may still be charged.
足以置你于死地 索伦
It's more than enough to kill you, Soren!
回头见
See you around.
这些人怎么办
What about these people?
－我们得告诉他们 －没时间了
- We have to tell them. - No time.
专注执行任务
Focus on the mission.
保持警惕 做好你的工作
Stay alert. Do your job.
他们不是陆战队员 好吗
Those weren't Marines, okay?
这里是我的家 他们是我的朋友
This was my family! My friends!
训练里可没有这一项
There's no training for this.
你知道吗
Do you get it?
Do you?
我得回舰队司令部
I need to get back to FLEETCOM.
拿我的装备
Find my gear.
和防御部队联系
Link up with the defensive force.
你也不是非得来
You don't have to come.
继续走
Keep moving.
－我们得离开这里 －什么
- We need to get out of here. - What?
他们来了 你们得赶紧离开
They're coming. You need to get out of here.
你们得赶紧离开 这里不安全
You need to get out of here! It's not safe!
你们得赶紧走 快点 你们得赶紧离开
You gotta leave, come on! You need to get out of here!
－你们得赶紧离开 －佩雷斯
- You need to get out of here. - Perez!
舰队司令部 快点
FLEETCOM. Now.
－他们需要知道 他们需要－不
- They need to know. They need-- - No.
士官长
Chief!
这边 快来
This way! Come on!
如果你想出去 就走这条路
If you want to get out, it's this way.
我对这里了如指学 相信我
I know this place. Trust me.
那是不可能的
That's not gonna happen.
随便你
Suit yourself.
艹
Shit.
快点
Come on!
进来
In here.
他们跟过来了吗
Are they coming?
放松
Relax.
你放松
You relax.
我看着你
I watch you.
那么多等离子弹到处乱飞
All that plasma flying.
死亡就在你身边
Death all around you and...
你却
you never...
我小的时候
When I was a kid,
有这么个女人
there was this woman.
她抛硬币
She flipped a coin.
她问我敢不敢猜 我猜了
She dared me to call it, and I did.
正面
Heads.
连续十一次都对
Eleven times in a row.
－真幸运－也许吧
- Lucky. - Maybe.
但我不是猜的
But I wasn't guessing.
我就是知道
I knew.
我一直如此
It's always been like that.
每次我上战场 我都知道我可能会失去一些人
Every time I go into battle, I know I can lose somebody.
我知道不会是我
I know it's not gonna be me.
这感觉一定很不错吧
Must be nice.
并没有
Not really.
艹
Shit.
哦 请小心点
Oh. Please be careful with that.
女士
Ma'am?
那把斧头已经有600多年的历史了
That axe is over 600 years old.
地球上曾有人用它砍过树
Someone on Earth cut trees with it.
好用市头来做燃料
Used the wood for fuel.
你 大块头
You. Big man.
那台打字机
That typewriter.
它对我来说太重了
It's too heavy for me.
女士 这座城市正在遭到袭击
Ma'am, the city's under attack.
那可不
You don't say.
嗯 那就干点事儿 打字机 放上去
Well, be useful. The typewriter, up there.
你得赶紧离开
You need to get out of here.
这是我的工作室
This is my shop.
在这一个地方待了 40年左右
Same place for 40 years, give or take.
看 放最上面的架子 麻烦了
Look, top shelf, please.
下士说得对 女士
The corporal's right, ma'am.
这里不安全
This location is not secure.
我们在去舰队司令部的路上 我们可以带你一起去
We're on our way to FLEETCOM. We can take you with us.
那谁来照看我的东西呢
And who'll look after all my stuff?
女士 这些都不重要
Ma'am, all of this doesn't matter.
那是个安德伍德便携机械打字机
That's an Underwood standard portable.
二十世纪的东西
Twentieth century.
来自康涅狄格州哈特福德
Hartford, Connecticut.
是在地球上 亲爱的
That's Earth, dear.
它经历了六次战争
It's seen six wars.
见识过共产主义 法西斯主义
还有所有介于这两者之间的主义
Fought communism, fascism, all the isms in between.
并且幸存了下来
And it survived.
现在 如果这都不重要的话
Now, if that doesn't matter...
星盟马上就到了 女士
The Covenant is on the way, ma'am.
现在人们说话的样子就好像什么都不重要
People nowadays talk like nothing matters.
那我们是谁呢
Who are we?
如果什么都不重要 那我们也不重要
If nothing matters, then we don't matter.
女士 他们要把这颗星球玻璃化
Ma'am, they're gonna glass the planet.
一切都将不复存在 你无法幸存
Nothing will survive. You will not survive.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
－女士 你明白吗－她明白的
- Ma'am, do you understand? - She understands.
走吧
Come.
这是什么 你的秘密地牢吗
What is this? Your secret dungeon?
监禁是次要目的
Incarceration is a secondary purpose.
这主要是一个实验
It's principally an experimentation
以及审讯场所
and interrogation site.
仅限海军情报局访问
ONI access only.
那就是地牢呗
So, like a dungeon.
他们越来越近了
They're getting closer.
告诉我 给我讲讲凯斯勒吧
Tell me, what's Kessler like?
他多大了 他大概9岁或者10岁了吧
How old is he? He must be 9 or 10?
－我打赌他崇拜你 －别说了
- I bet he worships you. - Stop.
当你那么大的时候
When you were that age,
你总是想要溜走
you were always trying to slip away.
爬墙钻洞
Climbing, tunneling.
我不想和你谈我儿子的事
I don't want to talk to you about my son.
父母就是会谈论自己的孩了
Well, that's what parents talk about,
至少别人是这么告诉我的
or so I'm told.
你有个孩子
You had a child.
所以 很自然地 我很想知道
So, naturally, I'm curious to know how much of you
你对他的影响有多大
has found its way into him.
我感兴趣纯粹是科学方面的原因
My interest is purely scientific.
扯蛋
Bullshit.
你知道我们这是要去哪吗
Do you even know where we're headed?
嗯 我当然知道
Yes, of course I do.
我记得
I remember...
你当时是最积极的那个
you were the most driven.
其他人是被招募进来的
The others had to be recruited.
－你是说绑架来的吧 －但你是自愿的
- Kidnapped. - But you wanted it.
从我第一次见到你开始
Right from the very first time I saw you.
你就想当斯巴达战士
You wanted to be a Spartan.
-我当时 6岁 -没错 你当时才6岁
- I was 6. - Yes, you were 6.
但你已经知道了自己的目标
And you already knew your purpose.
我也是
So did I.
你是个天生的战士
You were a born warrior.
－即便在你出了事故之后 你 －我的什么
- Even after your accident, you-- - My what?
你的手臂
Your arm.
放你离开真的很不容易
It was very difficult to let you go.
放我离开吗
Let me go?
是我逃离了你
I escaped you.
是我从你手里幸存了
I survived you.
我拥有了生活
I made a life...
即便还有阴魂不散的你
in spite of you.
我看这是一个很好的故事
I suppose that's as good a story as any.
靠
Oh, shit.
是等离子伤
Plasma.
等离了伤
Plasma?
－他们来了－拿着这个
- They're here. - Take this.
最好别在背后向我开枪
And try not to shoot me in the back.
这我没法保证
No promises.
放低身体
Stay low!
撤  撤  撤
Go, go, go!
－快走 快走 －走 走
- Go! Go! - Go! Go!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
他们正在从舰队司令部撤退
They're evacuating people from FLEETCOM.
这里不安全
We're no good here.
快走 快走
- Go, go, go, go! - Hey!
里兹
Riz!
我希望你别介意 我们没等你就开始了
I hope you don't mind, we got started without you!
－我需要武器 －自己拿
- I need a weapon! - Help yourself.
－你还好吗 －现在好得不行
- You good? - I am now.
我们尝试攻下舰队司令部
Trying to get to FLEETCOM.
但撞见了大约20个精英战士 他们一直在猛攻
Ran into about 20 Elites. They just keep coming.
和其他小队有联系吗
Any contact with the other units?
没有 他们抢先破坏了通讯系统
No, they took out the comms first.
明白了
I hear you.
持续火力输出 我保护你的后方
Keep making that noise. I'll find your ass.
我们得走了
We gotta move!
有办法绕过星盟的阵地吗
Any idea how we're gonna get around this Covenant position?
我们不绕过去
We're not going around.
好吧 给我五个陆战队员
All right. Give me five Marines.
等我们开始向桥头堡旁的掩蔽处移动
The rest of you are gonna lay down cover fire
其他人准备提供掩护火力
while we traverse to the defilade by the bridgehead.
遵命 长官
Yes, ma'am!
我们一进去 其他人立刻撤退
Once we get inside, everybody else fall back!
撤退到哪里 长官
To where, sir?
哪里需要去哪里 别在这里就行
Wherever you're needed. Just not here.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir!
－你知道你在干什么吗 －我和你一起去
- What do you think you're doing? - I'm going with you.
－不行 路易 你不许去－我不需要你批准
- No, Louis, you're not. - I don't need your permission.
我也要去 我可以救助伤员
I'm coming too. I can help with the wounded.
好吧 我们走
Okay, let's go.
嘿 准备好了吗     跟着你
- Hey, you ready? - On your go.
火力掩护   准备好了吗   走吧
Cover fire! Ready? Go!
你 还有你跟着我
You and you with me!
我们打中他了
We got him!
快走 快走
Go! Go! Go!
快 继续前进
Come on! Keep moving!
三点方向
Three o'clock!
路易
Louis!
放低身体 快走
Stay low! Move!
跑 快 快
Move! Go! Go, go, go!
我们快走吧
Moving! Let's go!
背后接敌
Contact rear!
正在掩护    补位
- Reloading! - Covering.
小心手雷
Frag out!
这边来
This way!
跟着我
On me!
快走 快走
Go! Go! Go!
快走 快走 快走
Go! Go! Go! Go!
我们得走了 快点
We gotta move. Let's go!
我们没事了
We're good.
达尼洛在哪儿
Where's Danilo?
里兹 达尼洛在哪儿
Riz! Where's Danilo?
他阵亡了
He's not coming.
亡魂
- Wraith! - Wraith!
火力掩护
Get some cover fire!
快点   路易
- Come on! - Louis!
尝尝这个
You want this?
我们得走了
Gotta move!
你走吧
You'd better go.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
这里就是我该待的地方
I'm right where I need to be.
快走 快走
Go! Go! Go!
老子就在这里
I'm right here!
路易
Louis!
来啊
Come on!
送你个大礼包
I got something for you!
不 路易
No! Louis!
里兹
Riz.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
这是什么鬼地方
What the hell is this place?
这里还有别的囚犯
We're not the only prisoners here.
你不是说自己知道出去的路吗
I thought you said you knew a way out of here.
科塔娜吗
Cortana?
哈尔西医生     对
- Dr. Halsey. - Yes.
快逃
Run.
退回来
Get back!
快走
Move!
里兹 穿上战甲
Riz, get suited up.
里兹
Riz!
我们走吧
Let's go.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
就这样了吗
Is that it?
你就这么去打仗
Are you just gonna go off to fight
一句话都不留下吗
without saying anything?
好吧 谢谢
Okay, well... thanks.
下士
Corporal.
看看运气如何
For luck.
正面
Heads.
很抱歉毁了你的休息日 士官长
Sorry to ruin your day off, Chief.
很高兴见到你
Well, I'm happy to see you.
我一直在清理下层
I've been clearing out the lower levels.
在防御工事建起来之前
Few of those cloaked Elites snuck in
有几个隐形精英偷偷溜进来了
before the barricades went up.
杀外星人我都快杀吐了
I'm almost sick of killing aliens.
还能坚持
Almost.
－里兹 你还好吗－凯在哪儿
- Hey, Riz, you all right? - Where's Kai?
我也想问你呢 她肯定还在外面
I was gonna ask the same thing. She must still be out there.
以我对凯的了解 她去猎杀星盟了
Well, if I know Kai, she went hunting.
我们也应该这样做
We should do the same.
我们正要去穿战甲
We're just going to get suited up.
战甲没了 士官长
The armor's gone, chief.
你说什么
What did you say?
我们的装备 战甲
Our suits. The armor.
它不在那里    狗娘养的
- It's not there. - Son of a bitch.
艾克森在哪儿     我不知道
- Where's Ackerson? - I don't know.
指挥部撤退了
Command bugged out.
高级人员也跟着走了
They took high-ranking personnel.
宝贵的资产   他们拿走了我们的装备
- Valuable assets. - They took our suits.
士官长 这到底是怎么回事
Chief, what the hell's going on?
谁在指挥
Who's in command?
－再给我们找点装备 －收到
- Get us more kit. - Roger that.
降低齐射率 为我们多争取一点时间
Reduce rate of the salvos, buy us a little more time.
收到  长官
Copy that, sir.
将军
Admiral.
在你爆破之间 我希望舰桥上的这群混蛋
I want as many of those bastards on the bridge as possible
越多越好
before you blow it.
我在上面   长官
I'm on it, sir.
他们拿走了我们的战甲
They took our suits.
我内心里还小小地希望你已经死了
You know, part of me was hoping that you were dead,
这样我就不用听你说 我早告诉过你了
so I wouldn't have to listen to this "I told you so."
恐怕你没那么走运 长官
No such luck, sir.
抱歉 约翰
Sorry, John.
你是对的
You were right.
钴队在维舍格勒殉职了
Cobalt was KIA at Visegrad.
我亲眼看到了尸体
I saw the bodies myself.
他们甚至不知道是什么攻击了自己
They never knew what hit them.
他们的两把武器都是满匣满弹
Two of their weapons had full mags.
未发一弹
Didn't get a shot off.
维舍格勒沦陷时 还留下了一个盲区
When Visegrad went down, it left a blind spot.
没办法知道有多少星盟部队登陆了
There's no way of knowing how many Covenant landed.
现在已经演变成陆战了
It's a ground game for now.
他们在袭击发电站
They're hitting the power stations.
我们在全力保护剩下电站 如果没有它们
We're defending the ones that we can, but without them--
－磁力加速炮就哑火了－没错
- MAC-array goes down. - That's right.
轨道防御灰飞烟灭
No more orbital defense.
星盟舰队可以长驱直入
The Covenant fleet can move into range.
－然后玻璃化－差不多就是这个结果
- Then the glassing begins. - That's about the size of it.
提利尔 天蝎号在东边机库
Tyrell, Scorpion in the east hangar.
－把 它开到舰桥上吧 －是 长官
- Let's get it on the bridge. - Yes, sir.
那我们的舰队呢 他们在哪里
What about our fleet? Where are they?
我觉得上级的决策是要保存
I believe the determination was made to preserve
我们最重要的军事资产
our most essential military assets.
什么
What?
就让致远星沦陷吗
Just let Reach fall?
他们知道会发生这样的事
They knew this was gonna happen.
他们早就预见到这种结果 于是做了权衡
They saw it coming, they did the math.
谁啊
Who?
我不知道 当权者
I don't know. The powers that be.
海军部 情报部 随你挑
The Admiralty. The ONI. Take your pick.
－是艾克森吗 －沒错
- Ackerson? - Yeah.
反正也改变不了这里的情况
Doesn't change the situation here.
让我说清楚 约翰
Let me be clear John.
我才不在乎他们的算盘
I don't give a shit about their calculations.
我要星盟为这个星球的每一寸土地付出代价
I'm gonna make the Covenant pay for every inch of this planet.
我们现在的任务是疏散尽可能多的人
Our mission now is to evacuate as many people as we can.
我能做什么 长官
Where do you want me, sir?
我们正在策划一个阻击点
We're creating a choke point.
虽然寡不敌众 但如果我们能集中兵力
We're outnumbered, but if we can concentrate our forces--
我明白了 长官
I get it, sir.
就像在塞莫皮莱
Thermopylae.
我的耳朵
My ears.
被手榴弹波及就这样
Grenades will do that.
请你放手好吗
Can I have my hand back?
你说的放我离开 是什么意思
What do you mean, you let me go?
你知道刚才里面发生了什么吗
Do you have any idea what just happened in there?
我们的敌人拿走了科塔娜
Our enemy is in possession of Cortana.
你刚才什么意思
What did you mean?
我看到了你的潜力
I saw your potential.
你的力量 你的专注
Your strength, your focus.
他们都指望着你
They all looked to you.
约翰指望着你
John looked to you.
你的强化手术失败后 我需要他靠自己
After your augmentation failed, I needed him to look to himself.
不 不是这样的
No, that's not what happened.
不然为什么你逃跑那天夜里
Why do you think there was no one guarding the ships
没有人看守船只
the night you ran away?
我们得赶紧上去
We need to get up there now!
帮我一下
Help me with that one!
我要怎么做
What do I do?
得把这些人运走
We've got to get these people out of here.
运输飞船从上层机库起飞
Transports are leaving from the upper hangar.
这边
Right this way.
This way.
没事的
It's okay.
靠着我
I got you.
让开 让一让 让一让
Clear the way! Coming through! Coming through!
让开
Clear the way!
约翰
John.
有什么指示 长官
What are your orders, sir?
拿着我的帽子
Hold my hat.
冈尼
Gunny.
甲板上全体注意
Attention all on deck!
把它带进来
Bring it in.
前面中间 跑步走
Front and center! Double time!
快
Move it!
你们知道我看到了什么吗
You know what I see?
我看到的是一群不好惹的陆战队员
I see some hard-ass Marines.
我没有看到疑虑
What I do not see is doubt.
我在这间屋子里没有看到失败
I do not see defeat in this room.
我也没有看到投降
And I do not see surrender.
是的 长官
No, sir!
看着你们的脸
When I look at your faces,
我看到了我们种族最好的一面
I see the very best of who we are as a people.
你用勇气战斗  用心战斗
You fought with courage. You fought with heart.
用爱战斗
You fought with love
为了并肩作战的兄弟姐妹
for your brothers and sisters in arms.
你们每一个人都不再需要证明任何事情
There's nothing left for any one of you to prove.
你们是我见过的最优秀的陆战队员
You're the finest Marines I've ever seen.
你们值得知道真相
And you deserve the truth.
敌军就在门口了
The enemy is at our gates.
数量碾压我们
Their numbers are overwhelming.
抵挡得了一时 抵挡不了一世
We will not be able to hold them back forever.
和我们站在一起的陆战队员
Any Marine who makes this stand with us...
都难逃一死
will not survive the day.
但你们不是一个人
But you will not make that stand alone.
约翰
John?
荣幸地为大家介绍约翰 -117
It is my honor to introduce to you John-117.
你知道他士官长
You know him as Master Chief.
今天 他不需要盔甲
Today, he needs no armor.
今天 他只需要内心的战士
Today, all he needs is the warrior inside of him.
你们每一个人心中都有同样的战士
And it's the same warrior that's in each of you.
那个愿意为家园牺牲生命的战士
The one that is willing to lay down your life for your home.
多拖住敌人一刻
For every moment that we hold the enemy at bay,
就能有更多的无辜平民登上运输飞船逃离
more innocent people can escape on the transports.
他们安全离开后 会向外讲述
And when they do, they will go forth
你们今天谱写的故事
and tell the story that you write today.
你们将会被铭记 你们是勇敢的女性和男性
You will be remembered as the brave women and men
牺牲自己的生命 让我们的孩了
who laid down their lives so that one day our children
无需生活在战争怪物的阴影下
may live without fear of this monster we call war.
现在 就让这些铁甲混账看看
Now, show those scaly bastards
他们惹错星球了
they fucked with the wrong planet!
解散
Fall out!
各就各位
Take your positions!
解散 列队
Fall out! Formation!
永远忠诚
Semper fi!
很高兴你在这里
I am glad you're here.
是的 长官    不 约翰
- Yes, sir. - No, John.
这很重要
It matters.
你的通讯器 长官
Your comms, sir.
通讯器 上将
Comms, Admiral.
你干什么
What are you doing?
你看我在干什么
What does it look like I'm doing?
这个时候 职级啥也不是了
Stripes don't mean shit today.
－把我枪拿来  －不 长官
- Get me my gun. - No, sir.
我们不能失去你 这还不是结束
We can't afford to lose you. This won't be the end.
今天过后 还有许多仗要打
There's more fight to come after this.
我们需要像你这样的好人来领导我们
We're gonna need good people like you to lead us.
约翰 我在这里也会给你们下达指令的
John, I'm still giving the orders here.
我们需要你能一直掌握指挥权
And we need you to keep giving the orders,
不然就给了艾克森那样的人可乘之机了
or else it's gonna be people like Ackerson.
现在拜托 把平民转移出去吧
Now please, get those civilians out of here.
那你呢
What about you?
我在我该在的地方
I'm where I'm supposed to be.
好好把握
Make it count.
一定 长官
You bet your ass, sir.
把弹药均匀分布
Get this ammo evenly distributed.
－就这里 各位 －好的 长官
- Right here, guys. - Yes, sir.
锁定装弹
Lock and load!
特雷尔
Tyrell.
让火力小组准备好
Got your fire team set?
收到 士官长
Roger that, Master Chief.
－火力小组 －好了
- Fire team! - All right, then.
保持各区域火力
Maintain your sectional fire!
枪炮准备好了
Guns are out.
谁能让我看看桥塔的情况
Somebody get me vis on that bridgehead!
他们来了
Here they come.
嗨 雅各布
Hello, Jacob.
凯瑟琳
Catherine.
还有
And...
索伦
Soren.
我也不想多嘴
I hate to interrupt whatever the hell this is,
但你们谁能给我指一条
but could either of you point me
离开这鬼地方的最快的路
in the quickest way off this hellhole?
上层机库有平民运输飞船准备起飞
There's a civilian transport leaving from the upper hangar.
我是平民
I'm a civilian.
你是海盗
You're a pirate.
是小企业主
Small business owner.
他们在哪呢
Where the hell are they?
天蝎 3X 我是银队1号
Scorpion-Three X-Ray, this is Silver-One.
请讲 银队 完毕
Go ahead, Silver. Over.
给桥头打一炮白磷 完毕
Give me one round of white phos on that bridgehead, over.
马上打 完毕 威利·皮特
Copy. One round, Willy Pete.
发射 完毕
Sending it. Over.
这还叫不醒他们
That'll wake 'em up.
我草 开火
Oh, shit. Light 'em up!
米兰达在这里吗
Is Miranda here?
不在 谢天谢地
No. Thank God.
她在哪
Where is she?
抱歉 我不能说
Sorry, I can't say.
开间房吧你俩
Get a room.
你和这人在一起
What exactly are you doing with this...
干什么
person?
三分钟 前我还是个海盗呢
Three minutes ago, I was a pirate.
有进步
I'm making progress.
他们把科塔娜拿走了
They have Cortana.
－星盟 －我亲眼看着他们拿走了她
- The Covenant? - I saw them take her.
一个向斐力和马吉
A Sangheili and Makee.
马吉死了
Makee's dead.
显然没有
Apparently not.
下士 把这些人带上船
Corporal, get these people on this ship.
在带了 长官 快快快
Trying, sir. Come on, come on, come on.
快点    一秒也不能浪费
Come on! Every second counts!
快快快 快一点 快
Come on, come on. Faster! Come on, come on, guys!
快快快
Come on, come on, come on.
这是最后一班了吗
Is this the last shuttle?
你听见了吗
Hear that?
听见什么
Hear what?
那是什么
What is that?
你要干什么
What are you doing?
快走
Go!
Move out!
我是凯斯上将
This is Admiral Keyes.
上层机库受到
Upper hangar is under attack
多支星盟队伍袭击 完毕
from multiple Covenant units, over.
运输飞船载满了平民
That transport's full of civilians.
我们帮你们争取点时间
We'll buy you some time.
途中掩护
Cover on the way.
快
Move it!
快   快
- Move it! - Move it!
火力小队来中间
Fire team in the middle!
加油 海军陆战队   你明白了
Come on, Marines! You got this!
给我吧
I'll take that.
平民都上船了 长官
Civilians are all on board, sir.
很好
Great.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
马上回来
I'll be back.
你能飞吗
Can you fly this thing?
你得在啊 长官
Not without you on it, sir.
我会回来的
I'll be back!
我们要去帮他
We have to help him.
不 帮不了
No. We can't.
等等
Wait!
佩雷斯下士
Corporal Perez?
是 长官
Yes, sir?
启动吧
Punch it.
我做不到 长官
I can't do that, sir.
你可以
You can.
不 放开我
No! Let me go!
雅各布
Jacob!
放开我
Get off of me!
有火吗
Got a light?
你让开
Get out of my way!
我起来了
I'm up.
敌方突破防线
Form up!
快
Go!
突破
Breach!
你的朋友吗
Friend of yours?
里兹
Riz!
士官长
Chief!
住手
Stop.
时候未到
Not yet.
不
No!